A few days ago, I told you guys about
neuromorphic architecture that could
operate virtual bodies in a virtual
world. Well, yeah, they've put them in a
spider robot. Not too dissimilar to my
favorite, which was a spider robot
operated by actual miniature human
brains grown from human stem cells, but
still really exciting. While growing
actual human brains has been a solution
for operating in a three-dimensional
space because AI just doesn't do a very
good job of operating in three
dimensions, it also doesn't do a
particularly good job of operating a
threedimensional body because that
requires nonlinear thought. When we're
talking about linear thought, we're
talking about A to B to C. When we're
talking about nonlinear, we're talking
about having to take ideas from
different areas and combining them in
new ways. AI simply can't do it, but
human brains can do it. Or neuromorphic
architecture that mimics the spiking
actions in our own brains. This is
taking the idea of AI, which we already
try to make look similar to human brain
architecture, and actually using the
spiking potential, virtual spikes that
we would see across our own neurons, and
that includes some degree of randomness.
In the virtual 3D body, these guys
actually made a lobed brain and found
out that they were able to communicate
with each other, but they needed to take
the virtual spiking, the random spiking
down a notch so it wouldn't have what
might be considered a virtual seizure.
What they found when placing the
architecture of a virtual brain into a
real body, it was able to navigate
through a threedimensional space, that's
what it's actually going to look like to
our spider drone. Oh, and you may ask,
why a spider? Why are we putting
everything in a spider? It's because all
roads lead to crab. You may not know
that because it's a zoology joke that
everything eventually evolves to look
like a crab. It's just a really good
body plan. Incidentally, it is quite
possible that if we find life on other
planets, we'll find crabs. They won't be
related to the crabs that are here, but
since it's evolved again and again,
yeah, I don't love crabs, namely because
I'm allergic to them, but I respect
them. It's also going to be less likely
to just fall over like a lot of the
humanoid bots we see. You may wonder,
how are they actually recording
information? Well, that's a concept
called a memor when it comes to
technology. It remembers that the
spiking potential was there and stores
that action potential between the
virtual neurons. Essentially, it
remembers that the neuron fired. So, the
next time it fires, it's going to be
quicker. That means that we can create a
robot that remembers the actions it
takes and perhaps can remember a space
more easily the next time it sees a new
space because it remembers the process
of actually navigating it for the first
time. That is not dissimilar at all to
how our brains work. It's going to be
similar for robots when it comes to
navigating, but it's also going to be
similar for different tasks, including
operating a body. I could see this
applied where you take the program that
was developed in one body and then place
it in another and it'll probably learn
it a little bit faster, but that is yet
to be seen. Now, you may wonder, what is
the application of this kind of
technology? How is it useful? You may
wonder, what is the application of this?
Well, a lot of the robots that we have
are extremely power hungry. In order to
get them to work, especially when they
are tiny robots, they're going to need a
more efficient system. The processing
for this is a whole lot cheaper and more
effective than trying to use our
traditional AI models to do so. What I
think this could be applied to are going
to be the beta voltaic cells. These take
radioactive substances like carbon 14
which is an unstable version of carbon
and is also a byproduct of nuclear
reactors. Researchers have combined them
with more traditional batteries creating
hybrids. That way it can actually take
the beta decay and turn that into energy
while also charging. So if there's an
immediate need for a charge, it can go
ahead and do that. Otherwise, when it's
in rest, it's going to be pulling energy
off of it. This could be really useful
for smaller robots. As for why we need a
wide variety of spiderbots, I don't
know. I'm just really excited for them.
Yes, they'll probably have military
applications, but can can I have one as
a pet? one that I don't have to feed a
glucose strip and keep alive because
this this seems awesome.